# Nicholas (Nick) R. Hood

# CPhys FInstP MRAeS SFHEA

102 Parkside Street
Rosyth, Fife KY11 2LT
☐ +44 (0)770 207 2652
☑ nick@cullaloe.net
portal: cullaloe.net



# Synopsis

Education and STEM specialist. Extensive international experience in teaching, aerospace and defence. GTCS registered teacher of physics and mathematics. For over a decade, I led the development and delivery of high quality initial teacher education in science at the University of Edinburgh. Specialist knowledge and experience of digital education. Currently pursuing doctoral research in the pedagogy of pre-knowing.

#### Education

Oct. 2022 – **PhD**, Edinburgh University working thesis title: Circles Around the Grit: a pedagogy for pre-knowledge

2003 – 2004 **PGCE**, Edinburgh University Physics and Mathematics

Nov. 2002 **B.Sc.** (Hons)(Open), The Open University Physics, Mathematics, AI and Complexity Management

## Qualifications

April 2006 Full registration, The General Teaching Council for Scotland, Mathematics

July 2005 Full registration, The General Teaching Council for Scotland, Physics

July 2004 CSci, The Science Council, Chartered Scientist

July 2003 CPhys, The Institute of Physics, Chartered Physicist

### Professional Experience

Aug. 2016 to Senior Teaching Fellow / Lecturer in Secondary Education (Physics

April 2024 **Specialism)**, The University of Edinburgh, Moray House School of Education and Sport

Aug. 2012 to Teaching Fellow, The University of Edinburgh, Moray House School of Educa-

Aug. 2016 tion and Sport

2004 - 2012 Teacher of Physics & Mathematics / Principal Teacher, Fife

1997 - 2003 Software Contractor, Cullaloe Project Resource Ltd., Cowdenbeath, Fife

1991 - 1997 Project Manager / Engineer, GEC Marconi Simulation and Training, Fife

1990 - 1991 Commercial Manager, IMACS (UK) Limited, Worthing

1989 - 1990 Technical Director, Aviation Resources Limited, USA and West Sussex

1988 - 1989 Chief Project Manager - Civil Aircraft Projects, BAe Simulation Ltd

1986 - 1988 Project Manager, IMACS (UK) Limited, Worthing

1981 - 1986 Systems Design Engineer/Project Manager, Rediffusion Simulation Ltd

1976 - 1980 Soldier, Avionics Technician Class II, REME

Résumé build date: April 7, 2024